# Surojit Paul

I have been working as a Full stack Developer for the past 8 years. Worked in 3 product based and 2 service based companies. I am well versed in Javascript, Node.js, AngularJS, ReactJS, PHP, Mysql, and MongoDB.I also have good exposure to AWS, REST API, Microservice, CI/CD Pipeline, and Docker.

9883618896

□ paul.surojit99@gmail.com

## **Profiles Links**

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/surojit-paul-401b94155

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/10950023/surojit-paul

Git: https://github.com/surojitp

Skills ———————————————————————————————————					
	JAVASCRIPT				
	Nodejs	Version used 17			
	Express Js Frameworks				
	Jest (Unit testing)				
	Microservices				
	AWS	EC2(Linux, Windows), RDS, S3, ELB, CloudFront, Lambda, API Gateway, Reddis, WAF(web ACLs)			
	Angular JS	latest Version used 8			
	Docker				
	React JS				
	MySqI				
	Sphinx				
	Mongodb				
	PHP				
	HTML				
	CSS				
	JQUERY				
	AJAX				

**Professional Experience** 

Software Developer

Alertrak LLC, U.S - Product based (Internally transferred form Brilliant Associates)

Full stack developer

Web Developer Nov 2019 - Mar 2020

April 2020 - Jan 2023

Brilliant Associates INC, U.S - Product based

Full stack developer

Web Developer Jan 2019 - Oct 2019

Brainium Information Technologies Pvt Ltd, India - Service Based

Full stack developer

WEB Developer Dec 2016 - Jan 2019

Park24X7 Technologies Pvt Ltd, India - Product based

Worked on php ,Angular,Node

Web Developer Nov 2014 - Nov 2016

Xtremewebs Pvt Ltd, India - Service Based

Worked on php and phone gap

## **Education**

PHP Certification 2014 - 2014

National Institute of Electronics & Information Technology(DOECC)

Done a Professional PHP Training on Regular Schedule from NIELIT (DOECC).

B.Sc 2006 - 2010

SAMMILANI MAHAVIDYALAYA

University :C.U marks- 45.5

HIGHER SECONDARY (10+2) 2002 - 2006

GARFA D N MEMORIAL HIGH SCHOOL

Board: W.B.C.H.S.E marks-45.70%

SECONDARY (10) 2001 - 2002

ARYA VIDYALAYA HIGH SCHOOL

Board: W.B.B.S.E marks-63.37%

## **PROJECTS**

#### Alertrak

It's an allergy matching app. Users can store their allergy, and medical condition list inside the app. When they buy any product they can scan barcode and see the result (against product ingredients and allergy list). It will also suggest to you the available alternative product. Also, the user can search the item and add it to the shopping list.

 $Technologies\ Used:\ Angular\ 6, Node JS, Express JS, Mysql, Sphinx, Google\ Vision\ API, AWS (EC2, RDS, S3, ELB, Cloud Front, Lambda, Reddis).$ 

### **Brilliant Search**

It's a business intelligence and data consultancy focused on the world of higher education.

Technologies Used: PHP,Angular 6,NodeJS,ExpressJS,Mysql,AWS.

#### **Deal-Connect**

It's a real estate app. There are two types of user Buyer And Seller. Seller will make a post with the property details.

The buyer can see the property and if they are interested they can contact the seller.

There are different Plans for sellers and buyers. As per their plan, they can make a post or see the post.

Technologies Used: Angular 6, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB

#### Windshield

It's a glass repairing app. There are two types of uses, Salesperson and repair person. The salesperson will visit the customer and make a request to the admin.

Admin will schedule a job for a repair person and the repairperson will visit the customer and finish their job.

Technologies Used: Angular 6, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB

#### **Rito Ride Sharing**

It's a ride-sharing app (like sRide). There are two types of user, Car owner(driver) and passenger(user).

From the Driver app, the driver can add their car(Multiple cars adding option is there) and publish their root along with the date, time and seat availability.

From the User app, Users can search along with there source, destination, date and time. They can send a request to the driver(Search result) for booking. If the driver accepts a request, the user can share the ride with that driver

Technologies Used: Angular 6, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB

## **E-commerce Shopping Carts**

It's a simple e-commerce solution. Used Angular 6 to create the front end and Express js for creating API services, MongoDB as database.

Technologies Used: Angular 6 ,NodeJS,ExpressJS,Mongodb

#### Park24X7 Parking App API AND Backend

It's a parking app for a parking solution.which has real-time parking booking and management.

Technologies Used: PHP, Mysql, Codelgniter, NodeJS

#### **Number Game**

It's a hybrid android application that builds using HTML and PhoneGap technologies and backend build on PHP rest API.

#### Academic writing portal

This site is built for set question paper and the user can download it.

http://www.academicwriting.webproland.com

Frontend :HTML,Javascript Backend: PHP Codeigniter

Database: Mysql

## **Hobbies**

Listening to music, playing Guitar, reading books.

## **Language Proficiency**

Language	Speak	Read	Write
English	Yes	Yes	Yes
Hindi	Yes	No	No
Bengali	Yes	Yes	Yes

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name: Let Sri Balaram Paul

Date Of Birth: 15-Jul-1987

Marital Status : Married

Sex : Male

Nationality : Indian Religion : Hinduism

Native state : West Bengal

## **Declaration**

I hereby acknowledge that all information provide here is true to my knowledge and if any discrepancy is found, I shall be solely responsible.

• Date:

• Place: India, Kolkata

(Surojit Paul)

Created with **TVisualCV**